Keuntaek Lee

Email: keuntaek.lee@gatech.edu Website: keuntaeklee.github.io LinkedIn: keuntaeklee

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are in the areas of robotics and machine learning. More specifically, my research centers around reinforcement learning, control theory, and computer vision. I study explainable artificial intelligence and safe learning based control algorithms for autonomous vehicles and robots.

EDUCATION

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA

Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering, PI: Evangelos A. Theodorou

Aug. 2016–Present

- Thesis: "Robust Deep Vision-based Control Algorithms with Probabilistic Learning"

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA

M.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering, PI: Evangelos A. Theodorou

Aug. 2016-Aug. 2018

Hanyang University

Seoul, S. Korea

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Feb. 2009–Feb. 2016

- Summa Cum Laude

EXPERIENCE

Honda Research Institute, USA (HRI-US)

San Jose, CA, USA

Research Intern

May. 2021-Aug. 2021

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA

Graduate Research Assistant at Autonomous Control and Decision Systems Lab.

Aug. 2016-Present

- AutoRally: Offroad Autonomous Driving
- AlphaPilot: Lockheed Martin AI Drone Racing Innovation Challenge
- Virtual Sully: Autopilot with Multilevel Adaptation for Handling Large Uncertainties

Honors and Awards

• A	mazon.com	Amazon Web Services Machine Learning Research Awards & Scholarship (75,000 USD)	2018 – 2019
• R	SS 2018	Finalist to Best Systems Paper Award	2018
• Sc	outh Korea	Government Scholarship to Study Abroad (80,000 USD)	2016 – 2018
• Ha	anyang Univ.	Capstone Design Fair Best Award	2015
• Ha	anyang Univ.	Techno-Business Capstone Design Best Award	2014
• Ha	anyang Univ.	Dean's List & Scholarship	2013-2015

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] **K. Lee**, B. Vlahov, J. Gibson, J. M. Rehg, and E. A. Theodorou, "Approximate inverse reinforcement learning from vision-based imitation learning", in 2021 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), Jun. 2021.
- [2] Z. Wang, O. So, **K. Lee**, and E. A. Theodorou, "Adaptive risk sensitive model predictive control with stochastic search", in 3rd Annual Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC), Jun. 2021.
- [3] **K. Lee**, J. Gibson, and E. A. Theodorou, "Aggressive Perception-Aware Navigation using Deep Optical Flow Dynamics and PixelMPC", *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)*, 2020.
- [4] **K. Lee**, G. N. An, V. Zakharov, and E. A. Theodorou, "Perceptual attention-based predictive control", 3rd Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2019.
- [5] **K. Lee**, K. Saigol, and E. A. Theodorou, "Early failure detection of deep end-to-end control policy by reinforcement learning", in 2019 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), May 2019, pp. 8543–8549.
- [6] K. Lee, Z. Wang, B. I. Vlahov, H. K. Brar, and E. A. Theodorou, "Ensemble bayesian decision making with redundant deep perceptual control policies", 18th IEEE International Conference on Machine Learning and Applications (ICMLA), 2019.
- [7] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, K. Lee, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Imitation learning for agile autonomous driving", in *International Journal of Robotics Research (IJRR)*, 2019.
- [8] Z. Wang, K. Lee, M. A. Pereira, I. Exarchos, and E. A. Theodorou, "Deep forward-backward sdes for min-max control", The 58th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC), 2019.
- [9] G. Williams, B. Goldfain, **K. Lee**, J. Gibson, J. M. Rehg, and E. A. Theodorou, "Locally weighted regression psudo-rehearsal for adaptive model predictive control", 3rd Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2019.
- [10] **K. Lee**, K. Saigol, and E. A. Theodorou, "Safe imitation learning for end-to-end control", in *Robotics:* Science and Systems (RSS) Workshop: Adversarial Robotics, 2018.
- [11] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, **K. Lee**, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Agile autonomous driving using end-to-end deep imitation learning", in *Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)*, 2018.
- [12] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, **K. Lee**, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Deep autorally: Agile autonomous driving via end-to-end imitation learning", in *Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS) Workshop on Learning from Demonstrations in High-Dimensional Feature Spaces*, 2017.
- [13] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, K. Lee, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Learning deep neural network control policies for agile off-road autonomous driving", in 2017 Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) Deep Reinforcement Learning Symposium, 2017.

PROJECTS

AutoRally: Safe AI-based off-road high-speed autonomous driving

Georgia Tech. Aug. 15. 2016–Present

- Developing ML-based algorithms and controllers for safe autonomous driving
- Funding sources: Amazon Web Services Machine Learning Research Awards, Komatsu Ltd.
- Keywords: Model Predictive Control, DDP, MPPI, Online Imitation Learning, Bayesian Neural Networks,
 Reinforcement Learning, Online model adaptation, Perceptual Control, Vision-based Control, Explainable AI
- Publications: 1 Journal, 5 Conferences, 3 Workshops

Virtual Sully: Autopilot with Multilevel Adaptation for Handling Large Uncertainties Georgia Tech.

Oct. 1. 2019–Present

- Developing ML-based autopilot systems for safe landing under uncertain situations
- Collaborative Research with UIUC
- Funding sources: NSF Award 1932288
- Keywords: Cyber Physical Systems, Costmap Learning
- Publications: 1 Conference

Deep Perceptual Adaptive Control for Safe Autonomy

Georgia Tech.

AlphaPilot: Lockheed Martin AI Drone Racing Innovation Challenge

Feb. 01. 2019–Dec. 06. 2019

- AlphaPilot Qualifier; Top 9 out of 430 teams worldwide
- Funding sources: NASA Langley Research Center Grant 80NSSC19M0211
- Keywords: Visual Servoing, MPPI, Object Detection, YOLO, Deep Optical Flow Dynamics, PixelMPC
- Publications: 1 Journal, 1 Conference

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, C++, MATLAB Version Control: Git
- Deep Learning Tools: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras Operating Systems: Linux, Windows
- Robotics: ROS, MuJoCo, OpenAI Gym Cloud Computing: AWS

TEACHING

Georgia Institute of Technology

• Guest Lecturer in Robotics and Autonomy (AE4803)

Lectures on Differential Dynamic Programming and Model Predictive Control

Spring 2020, Fall 2020

• Teaching Assistant in Feedback Control Systems (ECE3550)

Spring 2019

ACADEMIC SERVICES

Reviewer

• IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)	2020, 2021
• IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)	2019, 2021
• IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC)	2021
• IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)	2021
• Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)	2019